

🛮 (+1) 520-289-9886 | 🗷 paul.d.hein@gmail.com | 🏕 pauldhein.github.io | 🞧 pauldhein | 🛅 pauldhein | 💆 @pauldhein

Summary_

Experienced Research Programmer with a demonstrated history of working in the higher education industry. Skilled in Python (Programming Language), Data Science, Machine Learning, Software Development, and Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD). Strong engineering professional with a Master of Science - MS focused in Computer Science from University of Arizona.

Education

University of Arizona Tucson, AZ

2017 - 2019 M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS 2013 - 2017

Experience_

Research Programmer University of Arizona

ML4AI LABORATORY May 2019 - Present

- Built a pipeline to produce a computation graph from a program's abstract syntax tree
- · Designed and implemented automated sensitivity analysis methods for the purpose of model selection among multiple competing computation graphs of the same real-world phenomena
- · Assembled a parallel corpus of Python functions with their respective PEP standard docstrings from common Python libraries
- · Constructed a classification model capable of determining whether a given docstring matched a given source code function
- · Currently creating a stylistic domain adaptation tool for encoder/decoder methods

Graduate Research Assistant University of Arizona

MI 4ALL ABORATORY May 2017 - May 2019

- · Developed an experimental framework to properly test the effectiveness of various machine learning classifiers with varying linguistic feature sets; classifiers trained to identify biological context and associate the context with biochemical reactions
- · Researched and tuned several machine learning classifiers including Logistic regression, SVMs (with various kernels), random forests, deep neural networks, and a gradient boosted decision tree classifiers.
- Developed a parallelized experimentation suite to allow our experiments to be run on the U of A's high-performance computing (HPC) cluster
- · Developed visualizations of our classification results to aid in the explanation of our findings in our published manuscript

Undergraduate Research Assistant

University of Arizona

ML4Al Laboratory Aug 2013 - May 2017

- Created time-series fluent representations of different features found in musical data
- Implemented Allen Interval Algebra to analyze relations between features in time-series data
- Constructed a Long-Short Term Recurrent Neural Network (LSTM) to generate time series data
- Created a geometric pattern finding algorithm tuned for detecting repeated patterns in music

Student Programmer University of Arizona Apr 2015 - Jun 2016

LUNAR PLANETARY LABORATORY

- · Constructed a web-based data product organization tool to track a pedigree of all science products being created and revised during the length
- · Gained experience working with large multi-user databases, distributed computing resources and fundamental concepts in graph theory

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES SOFTWARE **Advanced** PYTHON, JAVA, JAVASCRIPT/NODEJS, HTML/CSS, LTEX Systems MacOS, Windows, and Debian Linux **Intermediate** C/C++, RUBY, SCALA, MATLAB, and MYSQL **Packages** NUMPY/SCIPY, PANDAS, PYTORCH, and SCIKIT-LEARN

Familiar COMMON LISP, HASKELL, PROLOG, VERILOG DOCKER/SINGULARITY, GIT/SVN, and MS Office Suite

Awards

Full Year Academic Distinction, University of Arizona AP Scholar with Distinction, College Board 2017 2013 2013 Wildcat Excellence Scholarship, University of Arizona 2009 Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America

PAUL HEIN · RÉSUMÉ **DECEMBER 4, 2019**